Young Gar, stop!
Stop! Stop!
Young Gar...
Otto, you idiot.
You went and did something
crazy, didn't you?
I never knew he had it in 'im.
To add insult to injury,
he even won Ram over...
And now I look like this!
Ram?
What happened to them?
What you guys are plotting
don't mean shit to me.
You didn't kill them, did you?
I told ya, it don't mean shit!
Move. I'm gonna smash up the entrance,
and put an end to all of this.
If you do that, the Sanctuary
will be closed off forever.
Is that what you want?
Yes, it is.
Every other damn thing is the problem!
What're you tryin' to pull? Huh?!
Garfiel, what are you so afraid of?
You think... I'm afraid?
You are.
That's why you're shouting and trying
to make yourself look bigger, isn't it?
What are you...
What the hell do you think
you know about me?!
I do know.
Because... I've been afraid of
many things throughout my life.
I lived in fear right up until today.
I left all the bad things in
Puck's hands so I could forget them,
but now I've finally remembered.
Shut up.
I still haven't figured out
what it is I need to do.
I need to find what that is.
But...
Shut up! Get out!
Don't you... Don't you even dare...
But you've already found that something
for yourself, haven't you?
I told you to shut your damn mouth!
You're just too half-assed, Garfiel.
It's true that Emilia failed the trial once.
I can't deny that she cried her eyes out
when it showed her a past she
didn't want to see, either.
But Emilia will keep trying, over and over.
Unlike you, the guy who
gave up and ran away.
Garfiel, do you have a grudge
against your mother who abandoned you?
Sorry, man.
We take off our shoes when
visiting someone's home,
but it's the Natsuki family way to trample
all over people's hearts with our shoes on.
Your mother left you and Frederica
behind when she left the Sanctuary.
And then... what did you do?
Frederica left the Sanctuary, too.
She believed you'd eventually liberate it,
so she left to make a place in the outside
world for the people living here.
And what have you been
doing here on the inside?
You want to keep the Sanctuary closed
off because you hate your mother
and the outside world
that made her leave you?
Because you don't want to be hurt here?!
No, you're... What the hell do you...
I don't! Not unless you tell me!
I won't understand until you speak!
If you hate your mother,
then bust out of here right now to
get revenge on her or whatever!
Don't take it out on the rest of us in here!
You hate your family! If you didn't—
You're wrong!
I... I...
Tell me the truth!
I... wanted...
my mom to... be happy.
We were in the way, weren't we?
My sister and I were in the way
of her happiness, weren't we?!
It only makes sense!
She couldn't even stand to look at us!
If you're carryin' baggage like that,
what's wrong with dumpin' it somewhere?!
Mom left so she could find happiness!
So I'm not holdin' anything against her!
But... I saw it.
I saw it in the graveyard...
Right after Mom left here,
there was a landslide.
And she died!
Why? Didn't she leave here
so she could find happiness?
Didn't she leave us behind so
she could find happiness?!
If she abandoned us only to die
before she could find happiness...
What are we supposed to do?
I wanted Mom to be happy.
I wanted her to make me believe
our sadness and loneliness
served the purpose of helping
her find happiness!
I wanted her to make me hate her!
I'm not lettin' you get
to the outside world.
Things changing ain't gonna
make everyone happy.
For a lot of us,
nothing's ever gonna get better!
I'm gonna protect them.
I'm gonna protect everything
and everyone within my reach.
I will become a barrier!
A real barrier that separates
the inside from the outside!
Garfiel!
The Sanctuary, the people here,
the old hag... I'll protect them all!
No one can do it but me!
No one will know but me!
And no one else needs to know!
Subaru!
It's okay, Emilia.
You're so damn stubborn.
I guess I'll have to force you into
total submission to make you realize...
that you're just a big, sweet idiot!
You'd better survive this, body!
Shamac!
Thanks.
Come on down to my level, Garfiel!
Wh-What just...
Is this... my sister's?
Damn it, why...
Good question.
Maybe there's a really hungry
cat hanging out inside it?
That's all the help I can give you.
Apparently, even when you can't talk,
you find a way to be annoying by glowing.
Look at me, Garfiel.
Huh?
If you want to stop me,
do it with your own hands.
Don't wuss out and hide behind
your blood, you spineless coward!
When are you gonna stop
taking me for a fool?
We're going to the outside world.
Emilia will take on the graveyard.
The Sanctuary will be liberated.
Whether you want it or not.
Who asked you to do that?!
Who said you could?!
This place doesn't need to change!
You know it's not gonna
stay like this forever!
In the same way we've all
been completely cornered,
there's gonna be a time when
you'll be helpless on your own!
It could be tomorrow... or right now!
Just go down, Garfiel.
Learn what strength in numbers means!
There had to be...
a better way for you to say that!
Take a good look, Garfiel.
The wall you're so afraid of doesn't exist.
It does exist! I am the wall!
I stopped here, and so did the
old hag and everyone else.
And that's the end of it!
That means it's over!
Don't just give up on yourself!
Whenever you think, "I wanna
do it! I wanna change!"
That's where your starting line is!
When you decide to lift
your head and walk again,
who has the right to stop you,
for any reason?!
Isn't that right, Garfiel?!
Isn't that right, Emilia?!
And...
Isn't that right, Rem?!
Damn you!
Talk about a bad first impression
for a new technique.
Come on, you've gotta be kidding.
Just how tough are you, man?
Don't you... underestimate me.
As long as... I don't break...
I can still...
Well, damn.
After all this, I have no choice
but to recognize your strength.
This is... the end of it!
No one else will ever—
What do you think, Garfiel?
This is what you call "strength in numbers."
Again... there had to be...
a better way... to say that.
Okay, then. All of our
feelings came together,
and our bond won us this battle.
I guess nobody can lift
a quain stone alone...
You finally said something that
sounds like it came from you...
That nasty witch was probably behind it.
That Sloth Witch Factor
that she talked about...
Rawr!
Unseen Hand... Unperceived Impact...
No... it's the invisible will of God.
Invisible Providence.
That's what I'll call it.
Huh? What did you say?
Uh, nothing.
You're letting me use your
lap as a pillow again.
I guess that's my reward for
overcoming my biggest battle yet.
Yes, yes.
Oh, Natsuki-san, you're awa—
Wh-What did you do that for?!
Shut up, you idiot! You jerk!
This happened because you went
off and did your own thing!
But I guess I might have been
in trouble without your help,
so it's not like I'm not grateful at all.
I don't know what you're talking about!
I'm glad you're all right.
Same to you, Natsuki-san.
Need a translation?
She said, "Don't worry me like that," right?
Also, "Don't get too full of yourself.
There won't be a next time."
That's where the extra rage is coming from.
Thanks, girl.
So... where's Garfiel?
Over there.
But... I don't think we
should interrupt just yet.
Interrupt?
Yes.
Garf, you're awake?
Yeah... I'm awake.
Then get off me already.
My feet are going numb.
Still ain't a shred of
niceness in you, is there?
When there's someone worth being
nice to, I can be nice.
Wha...
And I'm not worth that, huh?
Sorry.
If you want to hear a lady's true feelings,
try a little harder.
Garf, you're too stupid.
It's no use trying to think.
Huh?
From now on, fight with an empty head
and don't think about anything.
For myself, and for Emilia-sama, too.
Buh—
Don't be dumb!
I admit that I lost!
But admitting and surrendering
are two different things!
I could pick up where I left off right—
Stop yammering!
You lost, Garf, you purrfect loser.
How long must you carry on in front of the
woman you love before you're satisfied?
S-So you want me to just fall in line
beside the rest of you with a smile?
I accept that I lost, but I
don't accept that I was wrong!
That's right! I don't
think I was in the wrong!
So I can't make some
half-assed attempt to—
If you don't want it to stop at half-assed,
you just need to prove that
you're not standing still.
Huh?
The trial...
Can you change,
or are you going to be a little cowering
child stuck in one place forever?
Find out with your own eyes.
Don't say it in a way that
makes me wanna deny it!
Don't just give up on yourself!
You look as if you've made up your mind.
You'll be fine, Garf.
If anything frightens you to the
point of tears, I'll comfort you.
As a favor to an old friend, you know?
Damn it all!
First, you must confront your own past.
Mom...
You insist on going?
Yes.
Although I know it will
impose a burden on you...
I am not concerned with that.
The greater issue is...
how these two little ones feel.
You piece of shit!
Mother, I-I...
I'm sorry, Fred, dear.
I know this is causing so
much worry for you, too.
I'm all right... but I feel bad for Garf.
I wish we could go together,
but I'm just so clumsy.
I know it would be an
awful experience for him.
Fred, you're very responsible,
even for a child of mine,
so please take care of him.
No! Don't!
Mom, don't go outside!
Here.
For you and Gar.
Gar, sweetie,
your mommy has to go now.
Don't!
I promise I'll bring your father back.
Just wait until then.
My... father?
That's a lie... That's wrong.
You left here to find happiness.
Mother loved both you and me dearly, Garf.
She left the Sanctuary
for her family's sake.
Are you not content with that?
L-Like hell she did!
If she loved us, then why—
It probably made things easier
believing that she didn't love us.
If you believed that your love was one-sided,
you could justify the pain it caused you.
No! You're wrong!
You don't know anything!
When Mom leaves here, she's gonna—
Of course I know that.
Huh?
There's no way I wouldn't.
If Mother did meet misfortune
upon leaving here,
do you think Grandmother
would not inform us?
Then... Then why?!
You must know why you were not
told at such a young age.
Because, Garf, you are
no longer a young child.
In truth, you remembered that
Mother loved you, didn't you?
You have that scar on your forehead
because you wanted to forget her kiss.
You wanted to make it disappear,
so you gave it to yourself.
This is the end of your past.
Wait...
Wait a minute!
What am I supposed to do?
If you must rely on your older sister
even when she's still so young,
you will never find your answer.
I know it's pathetic!
But you're the only one I can count on!
Please...
What do you want to do, Garf?
I wanna do what I'm expected to do.
What who expects you to do?
The people... All the people who need me.
I wanna do what they expect me to.
And what makes you feel that way?
They made me remember...
that Mom...
really loved me.
So... Is Shima-san Ryuzu-san's older
sister, or her younger sister?
Uh, actually... that's kinda confusing,
so we'll save it for later.
Young Gar!
Y-Young Gar...
You see, I... We...
Don't make that face, old hags.
It don't suit ya.
Sorry I worried you.
Garf, how did it go?
Well, I can't say I really got any
results you can see out of it.
But... I do think I got some closure.
Okay, then, let's do the
rest of the trial while—
Now, that ain't my job.
That's right. It's my job.
Don't just go and take it.
Yeah, uh...
I also wanna say...
I think the reason I finally
accepted the trial
was probably because of you.
Thanks.
Did you just say "thanks"?
I'm not gonna say it again!
Listen up!
I realize I lost!
But if you guys liberate this place and the
old hags suffer for it, I won't go easy on ya!
Y-Yeah, of course...
Which means I'm gonna be here to
make sure you're not all talk!
So make sure ya do it right, boss!
Ow!
His face was so red!
Boss?
Between the two of us,
you're above me, though.
I bet you feel as if you've
gained a new brother.
You're older than he is, so be lenient.
Well, in that case...
Wait a minute!
Did you just say he's younger than me?!
Garf is only turning fourteen this year.
He's an eighth grader!
Are you going?
Yeah. If I stay here too long,
my resolve will waver.
Hey, Subaru...
About what happened in the graveyard...
Emilia?
Y-You know! When we...
Um... it means a lot to me,
so when the trial and everything
else is taken care of,
let's talk it over... okay?
Uh-huh! Uh-huh!
Talking now about what you'll
do when it's over...
You must be pretty confident, Emilia-tan.
I'm not sure.
Maybe I'm just putting up a tough front.
I know it'll work out.
I'll wager a date with you on that!
Yes, of course.
I'll be going now.
Go get 'em!
Watch out for cars and boys!
Don't be silly.
A giltylaw that came one step short?
Ya can't be much of a man if ya
keep lookin' all worried, boss.
The way you talk makes sense now that
I know you're an eighth grader.
I rattled off a lot of quotes from famous
people when I was that age, too.
Hey, listen... There's somethin'
I oughta apologize to you for.
Well, that's admirable of you.
Go on, then. You can talk to
your boss about anything.
Man, I'm embarrassed just saying that.
I saw you.
Huh?
When you, uh... you know...
got a little... desperate?
What? O-Oh, crap! I forgot!
But I mean, I wasn't
expecting you to come in!
But seeing that made me realize somethin'.
You may be a complete dumbass,
but I'm sure glad you're the one I lost to!
Shut up! Just forget about it!
You're not a kid, so
pretend you... didn't...
Wait, you are a kid!
Subaru, you dummy.
"Give it your best. I know you can do it."
"Puck and I are both rooting for you."
"When this is over, let's go on a date!"
You really are a dummy.
Dummy... Dummy...
Subaru, you nincompoop.
How could you break your
promise to stay with me?
I swear, I'm never, ever going to
forgive you until you apologize.
Hi there. I certainly have had
a lot of visitors lately.
Awfully bold of you to stroll in here
after that disgraceful display before.
Even I'm surprised.
You loose woman, who kisses up to
the first man to comfort you
when you're sobbing in despair...
You shameless fool, who keeps soiling
the world that is mine alone...
You utterly selfish hedonist,
who loves the you that he's forgiven...
Well, why don't you say something...
witch's daughter?
My name is simply Emilia!
I am the Frozen Witch, born in Elior Forest!
I won't give in to the
malice of a fellow witch.
I'm quite an insufferable woman, after all!
Nobody Can Lift a Quain Stone Alone